<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anthony on Adult Like the Rest</title>
    <link>http://adultliketherest.com/authors/anthony/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anthony on Adult Like the Rest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adultliketherest.com/authors/anthony/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Investing (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://adultliketherest.com/post/practical-investing-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adultliketherest.com/post/practical-investing-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Contents: There are so many things you can buy with your hard earned money that are more interesting and fun than investments. Especially considering that most of them provide some kind of immediate satisfaction unlike investments that are held for the long-term (20 years or more), which aren&amp;rsquo;t appreciated until you start withdrawing their returns in retirement.
From a purely financial perspective though, they are what you want your current self to buy for your future self so that your future self can spend that money on things that bring satisfaction &amp;ndash; like your current self does with that fancy dinner, new clothes, or latest piece of tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Investing (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://adultliketherest.com/post/practical-investing-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adultliketherest.com/post/practical-investing-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Contents: If you’ve read through the investing glossary or the first part of the practical investing guide you may have a good understanding of some basic but important terms and ideas related to investing. You may also be asking, what next? All of this information is great but its utility without a practical application is limited to factoids to tell your friends and family about, a Rosetta Stone for the financial news on TV or online (still pretty useful), and maybe a winning answer in a game of Trivial Pursuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Brackets</title>
      <link>http://adultliketherest.com/post/income-tax-brackets-and-rrsp-refunds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adultliketherest.com/post/income-tax-brackets-and-rrsp-refunds/</guid>
      <description>Contents: Income tax brackets are one of those financial systems that many people understand on the surface: a set of brackets (or ranges) that coincide with different levels of income that are used by governments to collect the appropriate amount of taxes from individuals. They’re also one of the systems that frequently get misunderstood: making enough additional money will cause you to move up into the next tax bracket and cost you more in taxes on that money than the amount of money itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing Glossary</title>
      <link>http://adultliketherest.com/post/investing-glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adultliketherest.com/post/investing-glossary/</guid>
      <description>Contents: Investing is intimidating for a lot of people.
The numbers and math involved can be scary, the potential for catastrophic financial loss is off putting, and the huge amount of potential investment options is overwhelming.
What makes all of this worse is a confusing practice common to a lot of knowledge areas: the use of acronyms and other jargon specific to that area. This makes it difficult for newcomers to engage and become comfortable with investing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortgages</title>
      <link>http://adultliketherest.com/post/mortgage-largest-debt-burden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adultliketherest.com/post/mortgage-largest-debt-burden/</guid>
      <description>Contents: Home ownership is an important goal for many adults as they progress through their life and start saving for a house down payment (cash portion of the purchase price) in order to amass as much money as they can. These savings (while an amazing accomplishment) are probably not nearly enough to purchase a home outright (especially in areas like the Greater Toronto or Greater Vancouver areas). If their down payment constitutes only 10% of the price of a home they desire, where does the other 90% come from?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RRSP and TFSA</title>
      <link>http://adultliketherest.com/post/rrsp-and-tfsa-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adultliketherest.com/post/rrsp-and-tfsa-explained/</guid>
      <description>Contents: They&amp;rsquo;re financial accounts that hold money for you.
Money here can either mean cash or investments of some kind and that&amp;rsquo;s where some of the confusion around them can arise. That opening sentence specifically uses &amp;ldquo;accounts that hold money&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;accounts that hold savings&amp;rdquo; because while both can be used to hold cash (like a regular savings account), when used to their potential they hold investments and provide a shelter from or deferral of taxes &amp;ndash; they&amp;rsquo;re tax-advantaged accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple vs Compound Interest</title>
      <link>http://adultliketherest.com/post/simple-vs-compound-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adultliketherest.com/post/simple-vs-compound-interest/</guid>
      <description>Contents: Interest is a payment made to someone for the use of their money. You pay interest on loans you take out for the use of the lender’s money to buy something like property (mortgage) or education (student). Conversely, banks and other financial institutions will pay you interest on money you “loan” to them &amp;ndash; more commonly known as your savings account.
In both cases, the amount of money paid to either party is determined by the interest rate: a percentage of the total amount used to calculate the interest owed to the lender and payable by the borrower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Critical of the Information You Receive</title>
      <link>http://adultliketherest.com/post/be-critical-of-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adultliketherest.com/post/be-critical-of-advice/</guid>
      <description>Contents: One of the hallmarks of being an adult is the ability to make decisions and handle the outcome of those decisions. Another is being able to recognize that you may not have all of the data or knowledge required to make an informed decision and need to find that by asking more knowledgeable people and doing research of your own.
It’s important to remember when asking people to share their knowledge, that they are just like us: they have thoughts, feelings, motives, and biases too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>