<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rrsp on Adult Like the Rest</title>
    <link>https://www.adultliketherest.com/tags/rrsp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rrsp on Adult Like the Rest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.adultliketherest.com/tags/rrsp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Investing (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://www.adultliketherest.com/post/practical-investing-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.adultliketherest.com/post/practical-investing-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Contents: There are so many things you can buy with your hard earned money that are more interesting and fun than investments. Especially considering that most of them provide some kind of immediate satisfaction unlike investments that are held for the long-term (20 years or more), which aren&amp;rsquo;t appreciated until you start withdrawing their returns in retirement.
From a purely financial perspective though, they are what you want your current self to buy for your future self so that your future self can spend that money on things that bring satisfaction &amp;ndash; like your current self does with that fancy dinner, new clothes, or latest piece of tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Investing (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.adultliketherest.com/post/practical-investing-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.adultliketherest.com/post/practical-investing-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Contents: If you’ve read through the investing glossary or the first part of the practical investing guide you may have a good understanding of some basic but important terms and ideas related to investing. You may also be asking, what next? All of this information is great but its utility without a practical application is limited to factoids to tell your friends and family about, a Rosetta Stone for the financial news on TV or online (still pretty useful), and maybe a winning answer in a game of Trivial Pursuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Tax Brackets</title>
      <link>https://www.adultliketherest.com/post/income-tax-brackets-and-rrsp-refunds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.adultliketherest.com/post/income-tax-brackets-and-rrsp-refunds/</guid>
      <description>Contents: Income tax brackets are one of those financial systems that many people understand on the surface: a set of brackets (or ranges) that coincide with different levels of income that are used by governments to collect the appropriate amount of taxes from individuals. They’re also one of the systems that frequently get misunderstood: making enough additional money will cause you to move up into the next tax bracket and cost you more in taxes on that money than the amount of money itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RRSP and TFSA</title>
      <link>https://www.adultliketherest.com/post/rrsp-and-tfsa-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.adultliketherest.com/post/rrsp-and-tfsa-explained/</guid>
      <description>Contents: They&amp;rsquo;re financial accounts that hold money for you.
Money here can either mean cash or investments of some kind and that&amp;rsquo;s where some of the confusion around them can arise. That opening sentence specifically uses &amp;ldquo;accounts that hold money&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;accounts that hold savings&amp;rdquo; because while both can be used to hold cash (like a regular savings account), when used to their potential they hold investments and provide a shelter from or deferral of taxes &amp;ndash; they&amp;rsquo;re tax-advantaged accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>